Fangqing (Francis) Yu

(626) 321-5848

fangqingyu2010@gmail.com

DATA ANALYST

Bilingual Quality Control (QC) and Manufacturing Process Control Data Analyst with demonstrated proficiency in working with large data sets and statistical reporting tools. Working knowledge of SQL, Python, VBA for data acquisition, processing, manipulation, aggregation, summarizing, reporting and developing metrics and KPI's, Proficient in Excel, VBA, Word, PowerPoint, Analyse-it, Python (Pandas, Matplotlib), Tableau, JMP and Minitab. Three years of experience working in laboratory quality-controlled environment. Familiar with HIPPA, cGMP regulations and SOPs. Fluent in Chinese.

EXPERIENCE

Genalyte, Inc., San Diego, CA QC Data Analyst

2016 - Present

Perform a variety of activities including data acquisition and processing to support various departments in analyzing and interpreting results for experiments, execution of protocols and other projects.

- Design and implement report templates for Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs).
- Collaborate with Operations, Assay Development, Engineering and Manufacturing departments to provide data reporting support
- Acquire (retrieve) data from various systems, formats and work within existing data environment to deliver reporting solution
- Maintain periodic reports including production metrics, QC inspection and instrument validation reports
- Validate, interpret and visualize raw experiment data using statistical techniques
- Develop macros and scripts in Excel VBA, Python to process, manipulate data, create visualizations and deliver results in client-requested formats or populate matrices (databases, spreadsheets) suitable for tasks.
- Attend meetings to keep informed of development and manufacturing priorities and activities.
- Maintain and update relevant SOPs for data review and reporting, as needed.

Q2 Trading, LLC, Albany, NY Intern / Market Research Assistant

2012 and 2015

- Helped the company expand their existing customer base by marketing to potential customers.
- Researched and reported on market conditions in company's strategic market.
- Collected, organized and interpreted data using software tools, generating reports on prospects and performance.
- Assisted sales and management with day-to-day tasks.
- Compiled, implemented and validated a databank of potential clients in the region.
- Developed posters, guides and classroom materials to help employees learn basic Chinese language to more effectively penetrate potential markets.
- Helped initiate, design and organize a regional trade show targeting local retail businesses.

Learning Assistance Center, Pasadena City College, Pasadena, CA Tutor 2010 - 2011

Tutored students on subjects such as math, statistics and introductory physics.

International Student Office, Pasadena City College, Pasadena, CA Student Worker

2009 - 2010

Proofed and processed thousands of student information records in an efficient and accurate manner.

- Created reports on prospective, newly-admitted, and continuing students on a weekly basis.
- Informed students regarding government laws and regulations, and deadlines.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Applied Mathematics Statistics and Probability, University of California San Diego (UCSD), San Diego, CA (Minor in Economics)

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science and Visualization Certification, UCSD Extension